welcome to category 5 technology TV what
V Quid genus technology TV gratam
you're about to experience is a free
ut sis usus est, liberi
worldwide interactive broadcast from
passim a worldwide interactive
Ontario Canada we broadcast live every
Omnes enim vivunt iaci Canada Ontario
tuesday at seven p.m. eastern time get
orientem ad meridiem Martis per septem dies ut
your questions in join the community
quod in civitas iungere rogationibus tuis
chat room at triple w category 5 TV or
Latin V triplex genus vel TV ad chat cubiculum
email us at live at category 5 TV and
Vivamus at ad nostrum genus ac email V TV
now let's begin here's your host Rob a
nunc de primo exercitum tuum huc et facias violentiam
Ferguson welcome to episode number 215
Numerum usque ad CCXV res grata Tacitus
of category 5 technology TV it's Tuesday
V genus technology quod suus 'in TV Martis
November the first 2011 and I'm Robbie
November MMXI primus ego sum Robbie
Ferguson's and I'm Hillary Rumble
Ferguson scriptor ego sum Hilarius murmure
greetings everyone thank you for tuning
Wisi enim ad tuning salvete omnes
in for another episode of category 5 and
in altera enim eventus genus et V
you'll be glad you did because we've got
laetus eris, quia fecistis Comperto
lots coming up this episode for instance
lots venire in haec res exempli gratia
in the newsroom densa da da china has
da da Sinis est in densa newsroom
revealed their latest super computer and
Super tardus computatrum et quisque eorum,
it's not powered by Intel or AMD OnStar
Intel Pentium sive suus 'non powered by OnStar
help subscribers avoid chance encounters
Signatores auxilium ne forte certaminibus
with monsters this halloween and a
cum monstris huius ac turpis
hacker leaked 90,000 social media
Forum gratis quaeque socialis instrumentis 90,000
passwords to prove a point change your
Tesserae tui quandoque probationes adhibere causae,
passwords people and lastly it's
Tesserae et denique quod suus '
confirmed hashtag ubuntu is entering the
hashtag confirmata est intrantes Ubuntu
smartphone and tablet market and unity
et tabella Mauris quis felis foro et unitatis
will help it get there stick around
auxilio autem ibi circa inhaero
because these stories are coming up
quia veniens fabulas
later in the show you want to know
deinde ad spectaculum vis scire,
something that's really kind of
aliquid quod suus 'realiter genus
hilarious and yet i just kind of notices
quodam modo hilaris et proscriptiones
that you're very very short tonight and
et nimium brevis hac nocte et ipsum
people at home were probably like she
qui sunt verisimile ut domi suae
usually that short is she I am short
plerumque brevis est et, ut breviter me
krista krista came last week for the
Ultima septimana krista krista factum est
halloween special she had this this
illa specialis blandit id quod habebant
paper crown so we're like okay we'll
ut bene nobis sumus charta coronam et si tibi placet
just lower the chair and and so this is
mox deprimere et sellam, et haec est
why this is what I just thought I'd
Quare hoc dixi ego mallem
mention that Hillary's not actually
Hilarius mentionem, quod est in actu,
three feet shorter than me there we go
pedibusque brevioribus me itur tribus
just thought I'd make the man I grew
sicut et ego homo sum cogitavi creverunt
magic of television people you know what
Quid est magicae sem nosti populum
what could happen if I his grew up the
Quod si fieri ab eo crevit
windows all of a sudden you know I could
potui vobis cataractas subito
lose 10 pounds they say the camera adds
X libras in camera adiungit eos dicere perdere
10 pounds
X libras
then I can lose 20 how you been I'm
Ego igitur quomodo esse possit XX me perdere
fabulous yeah I'm just good to see you
Non sum, yeah fabulosa bonum te videre
keepin it real I'm glad to be here
keepin verus est gaudeo quod huc
though yeah nice yeah I made a CD one's
yeah yeah etsi grata et fecerunt uno CD scriptor
called keeping it real did you really
vocavit observatio est vere realis exercuerunt in te:
and now you know the rest of the story
et cognoscite reliqua
whoo so hold on yeah the CD like I feel
ut supra memini CD sic sentio whoo
like there should be a chance for us to
ut sit facultas nobis est
hear some of this perhaps in future
aliquis fortasse hoc audite in posterum
endeavors in future endeavors perhaps in
forsitan studium et operam in posterum
future endeavors okay fair enough i'll
pulchrum satis bene usus futura Faciam
leave it at that give me the eyes like
tum mihi relinque oculi
what do you saying yeah you know a
Nescio quid dicis de te yeah
tonight we are going to learn basically
noctem plerumque scire ad nos
what we're going to do is we're going to
quod erant 'iens ut erant' iens ut facere
fall back in love with ubuntu we've all
Weve omnes nos back cadere in amore cum Ubuntu
fallen out of love with a boon to where
cecidit in amore cum qua impetratur
we are going to fall back and love and
et pergimus amorem incidere
for those of you who are savvy with the
cum illi qui sagaces
terms that is a pun so stick around
verba, quae non licet bovis et inhaero circum
we're going to be learning all about it
et discere de iens
gonna be a lot of fun tonight we've got
agnus dei esse multus of fun nocte Comperto
your viewer questions we've got lots
Comperto lots quaestiones videntium te
going on also our mobile site is
Etiam in nostrum site est iens mobili
available to you cat five dot TV /
dat tibi praesto cattus quinque TV /
mobile cool or I am I have dyslexia
mobile frigus aut ego habeo dyslexia
tonight I believe mobile dot cat5 TV
Credo mobilis TV nocte dat CAT5
sorry about that folks I'm sorry knowing
paenitet paenitet me quod folks knowing
me I probably set it up both ways just
Ego probabiliter me, et posuit eum in via iusta
so that I just in case I made that
ut non modo casus et facta est in ea
mistake but mobile cap five DV or scan
Errat autem mobile c DV quinque aut scan
that code with your QR scanner mm-hmm
qui cum codice รท QR-mm scanner hmm
built into your phone if you don't have
built tua phone, si non habent,
a QR scanner you can get one from your
QR a scanner vos can adepto unus ex vobis
device's App Store but that's a really
app est scriptor fabrica, sed quod suus 'realiter
cool site and this week we actually
hebdomadam hanc, et frigus locum cogitentur
launched version 2.2 we introduced the
launched version 2.2 introducamus
photo gallery the category 5 TV photo
Genus V TV photo gallery
gallery as well my blog can actually be
gallery mei blog potest etiam actualiter
read directly in the mobile app oh no
app mobile o non directe est in lege
effect awesome totally are sometimes you
terribilis autem quaedam inveniuntur quae sunt effectus, prorsus
can find out a little bit about what's
potes reperire ex exigua circa quis '
going on behind the scenes certainly the
certe enim agatur post scaenae
photo gallery is something to get
ut aliquid sit gallery
excited about though know if you've
quia etsi concitatae si quid habes,
checked it out lately cat category five
cat genus continui quinque nuper
dot TV head on over to our website and
TV et dat capitis in super ut nostrum website
what actually happens when you click on
quod cum fit, click
photo gallery there is a link for our
gallery vinculum nobis est
flickr gallery which is who hosts our
qui porticus, quae animalium nostrorum acies
photo gallery we have photos going all
omnes futura habemus imaginibus gallery
the way back to season 10 season 2
X II suo tempore in via
season 3 season 4 and now season 5 so if
III IV suo tempore et nunc ergo si temporum V
you want to check that out its category
reprehendo quod eius generis vis
5 TV and you'll get to check out some of
V TV quod youll 'adepto ut reprehendo sicco quidam
the past photos from category 5
V praeterita photos from genus
that we're going to continually keep
quod erant 'iens ut custodiant jugiter
that up to date for you as well last
quod usque ad ultimum diem quoque ad te
cool stress they are you feeling
frigus sentis quod accentus
sentimental check it out yeah and it's
Yeah look SENSUALIS suus
it's neat to kind of see how far we've
Ive 'animadverto quam longe sumus genus est tersus
come even that with the set i was
Qui ergo usque i
looking at them the other day blowing
altera die autem in earum inspectione flante exsurgebat
some more photos from I think season two
puto de duobus temporibus quibusdam imaginibus
and just realizing that wow that's
sicut et nesciebat quia verum est, quod wow
that's how things used to look around
Quod ut 'quam omnia solebat requiris circumspice
here it's wild we're growing we're
Hic suus 'fera nos sumus crescente
always movin and shakin always always
et shakin movin semper semper semper
mm-hmm so and I encourage you to go to
ac tu ad Mmm mm hortor
our website category 5 TV few people
V genus nostrum website TV homines pauci
have have done so this week and in just
hoc factum est mihi quia sabbati et iustus
a few minutes we're going to be talking
paulisper iens loqui
we're going to be looking at your viewer
erant 'iens ut vultus tua videntium
testimonials before we do that I
testimonia quae prius faciemus
actually have a picture that came in to
quod factum est ad imaginem actualiter
us from our good friend Andrew Jameson
nos amici nostri bonis Andrew Jameson
who's watching category 5 very excited
V, qui genus ipsum dolor suus 'vigilo
to now have the asus eee pad transformer
ASUS Eee codex hactenus habent TRANSFIGURATOR
and what's so exciting about that well
Et quid suus 'sic ut bene excitando
it's a tablet but it is running Android
sed ut suus 'currentem ad Tablet Android
3.2 point one and Andrew sent in a photo
3.2 puncto unum et misit per Andrew photo
of him checking out our website and
ei quippe nostrum website
while he's there he's of course also oh
Quis est enim hic quidem etiam dum
there we go there it is well he's on our
ut bene sit qui suus 'ibi est nobis
website but he's watching it the show in
sed suus website ostendo vigilantes in eo
the YouTube player directly on the site
YouTube et situs ludio ludius directe in
which is kind of cool because the
quia genus est frigus
iDevices don't support youtube so
et gloriaris non iDevices YouTube
there's nothing there if you're on an
nihil est super quod si vestri '
iDevice so that looks very cool now in
ut apparet in frigidissima iDevice
it I don't mean that I evidence support
quod non sit indicio, quod firmamentum
flash pardon me I should correct myself
facies mihi ignoscas corrigerem
wow so that's cool but so that's 100
quod wow sic frigus suus 'verum quod est C
viewer points i think for Andrew tells
Puto enim Andrew narrat puncta videntium
you have sent that in but I see an
sed video in te esse misisti
opportunity to present Andrew with an
Andrew cum opportunitas ut sisterent
extra 35 viewer points what how can this
Quid hic ostendit quomodo possumus extra XXXV videntium
be this can be I don't know if you
et hoc non potest esse nisi nescio vos
notice in this photo but I do andrew is
sed ego animadverto in photo est vestibulum
strategically held his well he's
paulum opportuna communitaque tenuit suis bene hes '
probably charging it directly from his
probabiliter praecipientes custodi ut directe ex sua
thermaltake level 10 snow edition
X Thermaltake gradu nix edition
chassis check that out that's the same
gb reprehendo ex hoc ipso
chassis that you see in the intro of
ut videre est in chassis de intro
category 5 team yeah that's really the
V dolor suus 'realiter genus, quod in yeah
server that we use to broadcast our show
et ostende servo nostro utimur ad iaci
it's from thermaltake usa.com and
et quod suus 'a Thermaltake usa.com
because andrew has has gone out and
quae abiit et fecit quod Andrew
purchased one of those and also has has
unus ex his quae habet et emit
included that in his category 5 photo ID
V quod includitur genus photo in ID
again 135 points tonight hey your points
heus te nocte puncta iterum CXXXV punctorum
so congratulations Andrew thank you for
Wisi enim ad Andrew ut congratulationis offitia
sending those in bacon and if you
si apud Baconem mittentes
like a ton of your points send us your
ut nos tibi assentior ton
photos of you watching category 5 I do
V vigilabo ego tibi photos of genus
tend to give bonuses if if you include
Si tendunt scisti dare commoda, si includere
yourself or your kids in the photo
te vel haedos tuos in photo
people watching the show if you include
populus spectans, si spectaculum includere
something like a device that we that we
sicut aliquid, quod non machinasque quae recognoscant
love here on the show and also we're
hic amor etiam ad spectaculum sumus
still we're looking for viewers to send
adhuc autem quaeritis mittere viewers
in their postcards oh yeah oh you but i
O utinam tibi yeah sed in postcards
love getting real post i think because
Puto quia amo questus post realem
we don't we don't generally get it again
non iterum nos plerumque non pervenit
that's true you don't get a lot of post
verum est, quod tu non post multum
other than bills these days yeah so make
praeter libellos ita memini diebus
our day and and send us on some that is
quae nobis et nostris temporibus quibusdam
not bill really nice you'll something
Non tibi placet quod occiderit vos vere delicatus
something from your hometown like a
sicut aliquid ex patria tua
postcard yeah your home and needs me to
yeah Francisci ivimus ad opus vestrum domi
see pictures of where you're from hmm
de quo nunc es, ex imaginibus vident hmm
that that makes me smile so we're
id quod facit me ridere et sumus
working on putting together kind of a
opus quoddam collatis
postcard wall still trying to figure out
Francisci ivimus ad murum adhuc trying ut instar sicco
how to do it maybe laminate or something
quam aliquid facere vel maybe laminate
yeah so that you can flip them over and
et memini hoc flip possis eas
read both sides I'd be cool so if you
Si utraque frigus legere uelim
have any suggestions for us hey let us
omnem suggestiones pro nobis ut nos remittebant
know and anybody who is joining us for
et aliorum qui nobis placet scire,
the first time tonight please say hi to
hi in nocte primum velit dicere,
Hillary in the chat room oh yeah my
Hilarius in chat cubiculum heu mihi yeah
buddy yes yes siree I'm just looking I
quod sic ita Im 'iustus buddy siree quaeritis me
me too I just like Greg in Texas yes
Mihi quoque non in Texas sicut etiam Greg
when I say post I'm talking mail the
cum dico mail post me locuti sunt
snail mail some may call it because in a
aliqui dicunt quod in cochlea mail
seemingly slower and archaic compared to
priscas et tardius videtur comparari
say I'm email yes indeed but we still
dicunt quod sic quidem sed tamen inscriptio non sum
love it and there's just to make
illic 'iustus amo et facere
something like really nice and special
quasi aliquid vere specialis eu et
and sentimental it like a tangible
et animi sensus veluti manu tacta est simile
handwritten letter mm-hmm it's just
hmm manuscripta litteras mm-suus 'iustus
beautiful you're gonna start getting
Pulchra es satus questus amet
letters let's blame the mail bag every
Email reprehendo peram in litteris scriptor
every Tuesday me dear tillery another
lisdem diebus Martis mei carissimi omnem alium
one for Hillary one for Hillary that
unus est enim Hilarius enim, quod Hilarius
would make my day I'm not gonna lie but
Im 'non agnus dei esse meum in die mendacium et
you just send them to Robbie to
ad te mittere Robbie
something just include me and it's
quod suus 'iustus et includere
always going to commit it's gonna say
Dicunt suus 'agnus dei iturus committere semper
dear Hillary and the bald guy or
neque calvitium et Hilarius mi Guido
something crazy like that oh the nerd no
quid insanis illa tamquam utinam ne in Nerd
I nerd somebody called me adorable once
Non venerandum Nerd quis mihi dicta semel,
I do recall that then you uh held on to
Memini, quid mihi et tibi est uh tenuit in
that little gem for a long time I gave
gem parum diu dedi
you a billion viewer points
a billion puncta videntium te
for that one I'm billion speaking of
quod est loqui de me billion
people sending us little kudos and
et qui misit nos paulo kudos
saying hello I'll I love to receive your
Et dixit salve amo te accipere
viewer testimonials Hillary's got some
Hilarius de testimoniis obtinuit quidam videntium
to look at tonight but category 5 TV if
V, si TV nocte intueri autem genus
you head on over to our website you'll
in capite et in nostrum website youll
be able to submit yours on the interact
posse submittere tuum in se occurrunt
menu and I encourage you to do that it
menu quod hortor ut facias
means a lot Steve those oh yeah got one
Steve got multus est illi oh unum yeah
here from weapons of mass instruction
hic instruit armis molis
from northern Manitoba saying schweet I
Manitoba schweet septentrionalem a me dicens
found a link here yesterday while
hie hesterno die dum inveniri link
scoping out some CC licensed music for
scoping quidam de CC licensed for musica
my AV classes might have been while I
dum mihi fuisset ordo VULGATE
was watching the WoW video for code
video enim esse spectant buy vilis LATRO codice
monkey to them and I got drawn in
Simia adductus sum in eis
watching the last episode this morning
Hoc mane vigilabo ad ultima episodes
now your bookmarked and I'll be stopping
vestri autem et bookmarked Et erit finis
by often great idea great show and I
a magna idea saepius ostendunt magna et
can't wait to find the time to wander
invenire possunt non expectare ad ad erraverunt
through your archives I started sticking
EGO coepi per adhaerente vestra archives
my toes into linux a couple of years ago
ac pedum meorum in Linux a duobus abhinc annis
but everything else got going on in my
omne autem aliud agatur got in mea
life and some pretty solid resistance to
vita et vi resistentiae coniunctas solidum pulchellus
being able to try to installing it at
insertis ad experiri potuerunt
work and it really wrapped my head
et operuit caput meum vere operari
around how it works I look forward to
circa quam operatur Exspecto
picking up some new ideas and I'm going
Eo picking sursum nonnullus new ideas et
to probably have some questions lots of
est verisimile have lots of quaestiones aliquot
questions thank you for what you're
gratias ago tibi, quia tu quae quaestiones
doing and from what I've seen you're
et vidi quod tu facis
doing it well thank you thank you very
tam vehementer agere gratias ago
much yeah we love to hear from you got
yeah amamus multum got a te audire
another one here coming to us from Rome
hic alteram Roma ad nos
asked curtain natus sorry from segment
natus ex parte contristati sagum interrogavit
wrong from Berlin Germany and he also
Berlin quoque iniuriae
included a picture which is really cool
qui est imago includitur vere frigus
hi ravi i'm using a boon to for a couple
Hi ravi Im 'usura beneficium dat, ut pro duobus
of weeks now found your site about two
De situ tuo duo weeks nunc et inventus est
weeks ago and downloaded some shows
weeks ago ostendit quod aliqua downloaded
great work i like it so much greetings
salutem magnam tantopere placet
from germany sure sweet and what let's
Dulce et a Germania certus quod lets '
just do one more this comes to us from
sicut unus ex nobis magis
dan saying i learned how to use HTML in
ego didici dicere quam ut HTML in Dan
two thousand but had no idea about
duo milia ferme et nesciebant
designing or using existing designs and
vel cogitaret existentium per destinatis,
the category 5 web design series explain
Genus V seriem explicate consilio telam
that very well completing my
Qui bene peragat mea
understanding so cool thank you thank
gratias ago tibi intellectus, et frigus
you for sending us that way yeah I love
Amo te ad nos sic Yeah
that a feature of the show is has helped
quod est a pluma has ostendo is adiuvisti
to take you kinda to the next level with
pius in gradum tollere
with your knowledge and greets everybody
Salutat te omnes scientiae
else realm asked as well
aliud quoque realm interrogavit
joining us from Germany and we
et veniendo Germanorum
appreciate your viewer testimonials keep
bene tuum custodiam testimonia videntium
them coming category 5 TV and you can
venit illa et genus V TV potest,
send one in on the interact menu mm-hmm
Mitte unam de menu penitus Mmm mm
please do we will we will be right back
placet fac nos erimus ius retro
after this message from our sponsors
Mauris post haec
they're getting the road or the dusty
ipsi erant 'questus in via vel pulveream
trails liquid image Canada captures the
liquid captures trahit imago in Canada,
action with a true point of view HD
actio vero cum parte HD
video camera directly into a
directe in a video camera
high-quality amex goggle it records
summus enim refert qualis stantes amex
every bit of the excitement exactly how
omnis frenum de trepidationem ut prorsus
you see it
et videtis
if my octane isn't your thing take a
octane si mihi tua res est non accipies
relaxing underwater adventure and
et ruptis disciplinae vinculis underwater adventure
capture it forever in high definition
princeps definition ceperunt eam in aeternum
video with a high quality underwater
a high quality, cum video underwater
camera mask from liquid image Canada
umor larva, ex imagine camera Canada,
perfect for the enthusiast snorkeler or
ad perfectam studiosum vel snorkeler
the deep sea diver check out the entire
Lorem tota Saxonia alto
line of camera masks for every sport
Omnis lusus diam personis mensura
liquid image canada.com this is category
hoc est liquidi genus imaginem canada.com
5 technology TV you will find us online
V online technology TV nobis vestrum adprehendet vos
triple w category 5 TV join us in the
Latin iungere nobis ad triplex genus V TV
chat room during the live show and of
et ostende vivere in chat cubiculum
course there are people including myself
Sunt sane etiam ipse
and and some of the co-hosts kind of
et Stephani co-moderatores, et ex genere
mosey on in throughout the week so make
Mosey ita ut in per totam septimanam
sure you check us out category 5 TV and
certus vos reprehendo sicco nostrum genus ac TV V
you'll find the chat room on the
youll 'reperio a locus in chat
interact menu mm-hmm and you can get
hmm mm menu penitus, quod ut vos can
your questions in that way you can email
Quaestiones in via tua, ut possis email
us live at category five dot TV you can
genus apud nos vivunt TV quinque dat vos can
tweet us to tweet us at Robbie Ferguson
nos ad Tweet Tacitus Tweet nobis ad Robbie
at Hillary rumble remember me I know
Hilarius murmur ad novi memini me
tonight's episode is brought to you in
hac nocte episode veniunt ad vos
part by of course eco alkalines
partim quidem eco alkalines
batteries at cat five dot TV / eco they
cat ad apicem TV eu gravida quinque / Eco sunt
are the official batteries of category 5
officialis eu gravida sunt ex V genus
technology TV and they power all of our
TV power technology, et omnes nos
battery-operated devices check them out
Pugna-operandum adinventiones eorum reprimendam
cap five TV / eco and the fantastic
c quinque TV / Eco et in fantastic
sound tonight of course is brought to
hac voce utique ad
you by music pro in the south end of
ab aquilone in fine Iordanis ad musicam pro vobis
berry you can visit them online cat5 TV
et baca visitare potes online CAT5 TV
/ music pro and while they while they
/ Et pro musica dum autem dum illi
don't have an online store I was talking
an online copia non sum loquentes
to them and they said you know I pick up
Ego colligunt usque ad eos, et ait: Scitis
the phone give them a call at music pro
in phone vocatio ad musicam pro eis
cat five dot TV / music pro for the info
cat quinque dat TV / ad musicam pro info
they'll hook you up with instruments PA
PA camur te erunt instrumenta
systems whatever you need lighting
systems lux lucis quod debes
accessories for DJing anything at all
Nam tincidunt omnino DJing
they've got it there if it's a
ipsi Reperi si illic 'a
multimedia piano oh yeah everything
O yeah omnia piano multimedia
brilliant store but they'll ship to you
egregia copia youll 'navem illi autem ad vos
if you're in Canada or the US so do
Si vestri 'non in Canada et US et
check them out cat5 TV / music pro geez
reprehendo sicco eorum CAT5 TV / Musica pro geez
eagle in the chat room says cool beans
Aquila in chat cubiculum dicit fabam frigus
and and it is cool beans everything we
et fabam frigus et omne quod fecimus
do is your tagline so much so that I in
ita ut non sit tantum in tagline
fact have a little something for you
eo minus habeo quod pro vobis
tonight I could not find cool beans for
Non potui invenire frigus in nocte fabam
you but I did indeed find you a cool
sed non tu quidem vir frigus adprehendet vos
bean oh it's a jumping bean and it has
O faba quoque suus 'a saliendo et faba quoque habet
it has amazed that you can you know put
tu scis quod posuit ea quae stupet
that on your desk and holy that remember
et quod sancti, qui in vestri desk recordabor
very special moment look guys it's a
quo potissimum respicere illud guys
jumping bean it's jumping all over the
faba quoque saliendum desilimus suus 'super omnia,
place it like races through whoa what
Eheu quid poneretur sicut genus per
was it I saw recently where is Oh Idiot
quis est enim vidi nuper O stulte
Abroad idiot abroad with karl Pilkington
Karl Pilkington et foris foris idiota
he was looking desperately for a jumping
respiciens autem quod maxime in ferventis,
bean in Mexico have one and he couldn't
fabae Mexico potuit una
find one called Mexican jumping beans
dicitur aliquis saliendo reperire faba purus
right so he is expected that he could
ideo bene sperare poterat
find one there and he didn't find one so
invenies illic qui unus est et non invenies
Carl if you're watching i'll send you a
Carl si vos vigilo ego mitto te, sit tibi
Mexican jumping bean Thank You Robbie
Tibi gratias ago tibi faba purus ferventis, Robbie
thanks Sophie I just saw that I thought
Sophia gratias ago tibi sicut cogitavi ut vidit
that's hilarious that's hilarious a
quod suus hilaris et quod suus hilaris
special present are you all right all of
nunc iure peculiari omnes vos omnes
it and you know what else I love fewer
et tu scis quod amem aliud paucioribus
emails hmm we love your emails that's
hmm emails quod suus 'non amo vestri emails
how we communicate in a timely fashion
quomodo opportune communicet
in the email the computer uh yeah would
uh in computer inscriptio esset yeah
you like to like to answer some
Vis aliqua ut responde
questions because I've got lots and are
Ego got quaestiones propter quod es lots
you guys so thanks for sending them in
Itaque propter eos mitteret guys
this question in particular comes to us
hoc maxime fit nobis quaestio
from drumstick hey y'all that is a
heu modo vestra quae est a clavicula
Georgia us greeting well how did do
Georgia, salutem nobis quoque quomodo faciunt
wondering here's my question for Robbie
hinc admiratio ut mihi quaestio Robbie
after upgrading to a boon to eleven
Undecim autem impetratur instalar
point 10 from 11 point oh four I decided
XI punctum O a puncto X quattuor decrevi
to reinstall 11.04 and since I had like
Ego quoque amo ut restituo atque 11.04
a slash home on a separate partition I
Et separabis partem a VULNUS in domum
formatted and install 11.4 all is fine
et denique omnia quae formatae sint install 11,4
except I cannot write files to my
Non possum scribere mihi nisi files
external USB drive and get a no space
USB coegi externum absque spatio, et a
left error through the drive okay um
Bonus reliquit errorem coegi um
although the drive does matt sorry yep
Vidi etiam sollicitus coegi: Matth
there are still space on the USB Drive
USB Coegi sunt ibi usque in spatium
this box is all Intel except for
hoc arca archa est nisi Intel
graphics which are Nvidia and the hard
graphics et duris quae NVIDIA
drives are Western Digital so where
sic, ubi Western Digital sumus foras
should I look and what suggestions you
Consilia et quaeram te
have to fix this hmm great show cool
hmm hoc magnum frigus figere ostende mihi
staff
virgam
prizes oh dear b-e-a-utiful women and
o cara Bea-utiful donis ac mulieres
great support what else would anyone be
quod firmamentum sit aliud esse alicuius magni
doing where's the adorable host ah
ubi exercitus faciebat ei ado-
garble co-host yeah he says thanks a lot
yeah dicit gratias garble cooperatores exercitum multum
for your help so adorable host Ryan come
Venerandum tuum auxilium et venit ad exercitum Bruno
on make me feel good Robbie of you lost
super me sentire perdidit ex vobis boni Robbie
weight thank you okay all right it
Pondus autem omnia bene gratias
sounds to me like you've got a
mihi sonat sicut te possedi
permissions issue either on your mount
utere vel permissiones exitus
point or the drive itself okay you've
vel bene, tu iam coegi ipsum
moved everything over perhaps you
quae movetur super fortasse
recreated so you've reinstalled Ubuntu
et recreantur animi tu reinstalled Ubuntu
but the permissions on that drive belong
sed licentias quas pertinent ea coegi
to your old install so sounds to me like
ut install altum velut natus ad me
it's strictly a permissions issue way
suus 'via stricte exitus permissiones
that you can tell that is to go into
ut possis dicere id est ut iret in Macedoniam
your terminal and type this sudo su do
vestri terminatio quod typus huic sudo an non
space nautilus nau TI l us and what
Nautio et nostri loci nau TI L
that's going to do you don't want to use
quod suus 'iens tibi non vis utere
that to do much okay because that's
quod facere multum, quia quod suus 'okay
dangerous but it will tell you if you go
sed si tu tibi gravis
to that drive and you're able to create
coegi et ad id te posse creare
folders and move things around it will
circa folder erit movemur
tell you that hey yeah you it's just a
amen dico vobis, quod suus 'iustus a heus tu yeah
permissions thing because by typing sudo
res per typing sudo permissiones
nautilus you're basically running
Nautilus plerumque currentem tu
nautilus your file browser as a super
Super lima ut vestri pasco Nautilus
user the root user good guy saying hey
in user radix user heus bonum guy dicens
you can also use GK pseudo nautilus
Vos can quoque utor GK falsi nominis nautilos
that's if you want to hit alt f2 and you
Quod ut 'si vis alt f2 et ledo
don't want to have to go into the
nolo autem vadam ad
terminal I said you know you can do it
scire vos can termino dixi vobis faciam
either way but yeah alt f2 GK pseudo
sed utrumque memini alt GK Pseudo F2
nautilus or just go into terminal and
Nautilus vel iustus vado in terminalibus
type sudo nautilus so if that's the case
Quod si ita est causa typus sudo nautilos
Ryan which I think it is you're going to
Carl cogitare quod erant 'iens ut sit tibi
find that you can now read and write to
invenire quod iam legere et scribere possunt,
that drive so you can do things and that
et quia omnia potes et Coegi
just confirms for us that it is a
tantum confirmat quod in nobis est,
permissions issue you don't want to do
permissiones normam tu non vis ut faciam tibi
anything with it because you don't want
quod factum est, quod tu non vis
to you don't want to damage anything on
nocere tibi non vis ad aliquid in
your drive so what you would do is you
quid esset facturus est vobis ut vestri coegi
need to find out where the problem lies
e necessarium invenire problema iacet qua
if it's your mount point you need to
Si suus 'vestri punctum Mount debes
unmount the drive and you need to
infletus coegi est, et opus est
perhaps you know if it's just you on the
si nosti forsitan suus 'iustus super vos
computer try CH modding the mount point
Mount computatrum attentent in puncto C modding
to 777 so that everyone its world
DCCLXXVII in mundo, ut quisque suum
writable and readable and executable so
writable est et readable et exsecutabile
you can now remount the drive to that
iam coegi ad ad quod vos can remount
mount point and it should have
puncto escendere habeat
better permissions but if if it goes
Sed si quidem melius permissiones
further than that and the files
et amplius quam files
themselves are owned by a different user
aliter se haberet Disputatio
because you may have changed your
quia interdum mutata tuum
username and credentials when you
et documentorum tibi nomen usoris
reinstall the moon too so things have
et lunam et omnia restituo
changed as far as permissions go for
quantum mutatus pro licentiis
those files so it sounds to me like a
Sonat ut sicut mihi qui files
permissions issue do that check it out
Non enim ex eventu permissiones coerceret
CH own the files gadwal mentioning you
Habent enim memoriam vestri files C gadwal
can CH own the entire folder so CH own
CH ita CH folder potest in tota sua
space dash are with a capital R for
offendas ad spatium R cum autem capitis
recursive space whatever your name is if
si id nomen loci recursive
it's Ryberg for example space and then
exempli gratia locus suus et Ryberg
the the amount point that's mounted to
quantum divina dignatione iudicem factum est illud, quod suus '
do it recursively or you can do it in
facere non potestis facere in recursively
nautilus to determine what what the
Nautio determinare quid
issue is there Ryan and let us know but
Carl exitus est, sed et nos novimus
that hopefully that points you kind of
Utinam aliquid quod est genus
in the right direction but it does sound
desinit in rectum non
like a permissions thing just sounds
est sicut sonat sicut permissiones
like the files and folders are owned by
ut lima quod folders es amet
the wrong user if you need to read those
Si vos postulo ut lego eorum ad malum usor
files you can do it using that sudo
files potes facere uti ne sudo
nautilus and move things around and do
Nautio et moveri circa
all that if you need to but if you need
quae omnia, si opus est, sed si te postulo
to actually regain access to the drive
ut vere coegi neque accessum ad altare
so you come out to this home then you'll
et venistis ad locum hunc Chrys
need to you'll need to change the
necesse est ut youll 'postulo mutare
permissions on those folders recursively
permissionibus eorum in folders recursively
cool all right a Jameson warning yeah
corripientes omnem ius frigus et Jameson yeah
you don't want to do a recursive chmod
non enim vis ut faciam tibi recursive chmod
of 777 because then you can damage some
DCCLXXVII quia tunc aliqui ex vobis sit amet
of the access to certain files certainly
et quidam aditus ad files certe
when it comes to programs and executive
cum fit, exsecutiva posterum capiendorum
roles and things like that you don't
numeribus muneribus sunt tamquam quae non
want to do that this is his home folder
vis ut faciam tibi quod folder in domum suam
so most of it's going to be
Sic futurum est
configuration files and and documents
configuratione et documenta et files
and pictures and things like that so you
et sic quod velut rerum imaginibus, et
should do okay but he sang drumstick
sed bene faciendum clavicula cantavit
thanks adorable Robbie sounds like I'm
Robbie gratias cara sonat me
on the right track sounds like I love
in semita recta sonat amo
you well there you have it winner winner
bene est tibi victor et victor
chicken dinner drumstick dinner his
clavicula prandium prandium pullum suum,
name's drumstick in the chat room all
in chat cubiculum omne nomen clavicula
right Cheers I hope that helps yes and
Nam iuvat et recte spero Fremitus
at least again and points in the right
quae quidem saepius recta
direction there you go cool moving
tu frigus motus directione
onward and upward got us another email
aliud tendite, et supra nos got inscriptio
coming to us from Dan hey down saying
venit ad nos a Dan usque heus dicens
hello I wiped my 16 gig micro SD 10
salve mi XVI tergebam cisiis pervolavit Micro SD X
point and install using DD and then
et per punctum DD et tunc install
attempted to install from the minimal
conatus install a minimo
ubuntu CD it keeps asking to download
Ubuntu CD postulantes ut download custodit eam
items but i have no internet connection
sed non items conexio
this glue is unending and all options on
quo bitumine et bene in perpetuum est
CD can provide the same result how can i
Idem effectus non potest providere CD Quo uero i
get a minimal install without an
aequidistans a minima install adepto an non
internet connection Wow okay well that's
Bene quod suus 'okay conexio Wow
that's kind of a horse of a different
id genus alia equum
color last week dan was asking about
color ultima septimana de Dan rogabat
getting minimal install on his 16 gig
questus ad minima ejus install XVI cisiis pervolavit
micro SD card I didn't realize you
Micro SD card non animadverto vos
didn't have an internet connection that
conexio est, quae non habent
complicates things a little it sure does
quae non parum impedit confirmo
I mean one of the one of I think the
Ego puto quod sit unum unum
amazing things about Linux and the way
Linux de via, et miris
Linux and installs the way Linux
Linux installs et viam Linux
configures itself on boot is that it
quod tabernus ex is se conformat,
communicates with repositories they're
qui nimium ascendunt in repositoria
called servers on the Internet yeah and
yeah, et in Internet dicitur servers
make sure that everything's up to date
fac ut omnia ad date est scriptor
make sure that you have all of the tools
fac, quod tibi omnes instrumenta
that you need in order to operate your
quod vos postulo ut tuam agunt
computer so with you not having an
et non habens in computatrum tecum
internet connection you're trying to do
Penitus iunctio es trying ut faciam
this install and it's a minimal install
et quod suus 'install install aequidistans a minima
so there's a lot lacking from the ISO
ISO deerat ideo sit amet
that needs to be obtained off of the
in off opus est adeptus, quod
internet it can cause some problems yeah
interrete potest esse aliqua causa problems yeah
one tool that's kind of cool if you know
Unum genus est instrumentum frigus nosti
the packages that you do need there's a
packages enim ut illic 'a facies opus
tool called apt on CD a pton CD let's
vocavit CD de Compton aptum instrumentum ad CD lets '
see if I can find it here apt on CD dot
vide si non hic facile est invenire dat CD
sourceforge.net that's their website and
sourceforge.net quod suus website, et eorum,
this tool allows you to basically
Hoc ferrum sino vos ad basically
configure a CD that has those files for
configurare ad CD, ut est illud lima pro
apps so that you can set up a basically
apps potest statuere ut plerumque
a CD based repository so you can create
te potest creare, ita CD ad eclesiae reposito fundatur
a CD that then becomes a repository for
et quod tunc fit CD ad eclesiae reposito
your install so as long as you get the
ita ut install vestri sicut vos adepto per longum
right tools you know like if you need
Si ius tools vos postulo sicut vos scitis
for example your ex environment or
exempli gratia amet aut ex vobis
whatever it is that you need to get
quidquid id est, ut vos postulo impetro
without an internet connection it can be
non potest esse per illa conexio
challenging the easiest thing for you to
lacessendo factu facillimum ad vos
do because it's a microsd would be to
quia illud esset faciendum MicroSD
get ahold of an internet connection and
ut acidum desoxyribonucleicum est et conexio
set it up on that connection and then
et posuit eum illa nexum
you're golden once its installed sure
tu aliquando aureum et certus installed
you won't get your updates you won't get
Vos mos non adepto tua et non updates
the latest and greatest versions of you
Integer lacinia, quam a te versiones
know an office or libre office whatever
libre officio vel munere scio
you choose to run they won't come to you
vis currere sunt, non veniet ad vos
automatically as they do to internet
sicut faciunt usque penitus automatice
connected users
coniuncta users
at least you can get that install set up
certe vos can adepto ut install extruxerat
on that micro SD card and then you take
Et sumes inde Micro SD pecto
that card home or wherever it is that
qui ubicumque card aut hoc est in domum suam
you're operating without internet and it
et non penitus es operating
would be great and make copies of it so
codicibus et sic esset valde
that you can use it on your other
alterum, quod vos can utor is in vestri
computers without having to have an
sine est ut computers
internet connection brilliant thing
res egregie conexio
about linux is that you can make copies
Linux, quod non potest multiplicari super vos
not only will they work across multiple
Non solum autem qui operatur per multa
types of hardware in most cases because
typus of hardware quod ut in pluribus,
generally speaking is going to detect
est plerumque loqui ad deprehendere
new hardware and changes in hardware
novus changes in hardware hardware et
when you boot but also heard me it's
Dum suus 'tabernus, sed etiam audivit me,
legal you're allowed to do that in fact
ut in eo legitimum tibi liceat facere
you're encouraged to do that so in a
vos erant 'animarentur ad fac ita ut in
case like Linux you know you can create
sicut scitis casu Linux possis creo
your own drive and then make copies so
et sic multiplicari coegi tua
that you can use it on other computers
quod vos can utor in suus alius computers
and you're happy so easiest case
Et si vestri 'felix et easiest
scenario is for you to get ahold of an
sem enim propter vos ut in acidum desoxyribonucleicum
internet connection down create that
et quod creare conexio
thing with internet access that's going
cum rem penitus obvius, quod suus 'iens
to just make your life so much easier
iustum est, ut multo facilius est enim vita tua
honestly and if you can just you know
si potes honeste, sicut scitis
spend an afternoon getting it set up
Erexit diei questus expendere
exactly the way you want with internet
cum prorsus tibi in via interrete
then you're not going to have any
tunc vos erant 'non iens ut habeat aliquam
troubles and then you go back to where
tunc mala Restitui
it is that you have no internet you've
id est, ut non penitus quid habes
already got it created configured
iam got figuram creata est
everything's there you don't have to be
quae non est ibi esse
back and forth all the time but either
commeo semper uel
way you're going to need the internet
Sic erant 'iens ut postulo interrete
even to use apt on CD you've got to have
ut facile obtinuit ut tu quidem in CD
access to those repositories initially
aditum ad eos repositoria initio
so I think that's you know you might as
Quid si scias quod puto
well just build it with an internet
atque ita sicut aedificare cum interrete
connection and then go from there and
et nexu, et inde exire
then take it to a non connected
deinde ut ea non pertinere ad
environment cool makes sense I'd be
ego autem facit sensum elit frigus
interested to know Dan well like what
Dan etiam interested scio quam ut
what it is that is causing him to set
quod est ponere quod facit
this up with no internet connection yeah
hoc nihil est conexio yeah
like just of interest you know because I
sicut scitis quia iustus ex faenore
kind of picture our world is being very
picturae genere nostro mundo esset
connected these days like I can't walk a
sicut est dies haec quae non ambulaverint
few blocks without having Wi-Fi internet
paucos cuneos sine interrete Wi-FI
access available to any free so so you
et sic liberum accessum ad praesto
know where are you from or is there
scio et unde venistis est
something else that's keeping you from
quid aliud quam ut custodiant te
having internet access to be able to do
habent accessum ad interrete posset facere,
this but I think you'll be able to find
sed hoc puto youll 'reperio poterit
it anyways so thank you very much for
ut eam anyways gratias ago tibi quia diversi generis multa nimis
the question then mmm thank you looks
ergo quaestio mmm gratias ago tibi voltus
like we've got time for one more quick
Comperto velox sicut unum tempus
question I think fantastic this comes to
Ego hanc quaestionem venit in fantastic
us from Katherine McCleary hey Katherine
McCleary heus nos a Catharina Marcus Tullius
the AMD a-series LAN low ap use have
Series A LAN humilitatem habent AP AMD
been out for several months now and
fuit enim jam menses
there are several pcs available to buy
multa sunt available emere PCs
which use them how do they compare to
quae quomodo utendum comparamus
core i3 57 sandy bridge cpus for cheap
Caput LVII i3 pontem eros vili harenam
skate pc gamers like myself and my team
Nullam dolor meus PC gamers, sicut et ego
daughter her old pc legs terribly when
terribly filiae eius cum senex crura PC
playing dragon age origins and i can't
et ego non age origins draco ludens
play anything newer i play some civ 5
quod Augustinus dicit V de ludo ludere recentior I.
but mostly older games especially be a
ceterum magna ex parte maxime ludos maior esset
dosbox right okay sounds so i have a
Dosbox rectum et bene sonat habeo
feeling that I pretty much any modern
Sententia, quae pulchellus multo quis modern
architecture CPU is going to do just
architectura sit acturus sicut CPU
great for you I mean you're dealing with
quoniam magnus es tu, cum non sit
stuff that is very minimal as far as its
quia materia est usque ad minimum
requirements as far as the question
quaestionem quantum commodum
about AMD vs intel and things i think
Intel Pentium circa nos sunt, et Puto
that gap is really being bridged between
ponte gap inter id quod vere est,
the two companies because while Intel
quod cum duas societates Intel
was really pushing for the apu with the
erat enim vere propellentibus cum apu
the integrated processor with the
cum integrated in processus
graphics and everything AMD was still
Pentium II graphics et quae adhuc esset
very focused on the ax 86 architecture
LXXXVI securis ipsa focused architectura
and just later the i386 i should say
et postea sicut ex i386 i say
really focused on application launch
Lorem applicationem ad rem focused
times things that these days is really
quae semper est dies
not as important as really good
non est tam magna quam bonum realiter
performance in games and multimedia rich
ludos et dives in perficientur multimedia
applications being able to watch blu-ray
non posset vigilate Blu-illuminas ludio applications
movies and things so their focus is kind
tam benignus et focus Books
of shifted with the lenna is it leno i
et ego animus traducatur cum lenna leno est
think they're called there some hand
erant autem illic quidam opinantur, dicitur manus
lanolin the a series anyways those
lanolin in illa serie anyways
processors are really shifting the gears
processors fuerint anni qui re vera shifting
for AMD because they're finally entering
Intel Core pro quod erant 'intrantes tandem
kind of basically exiting that realm
genus plerumque exitus regni
where where they were where they were
in quo erant ibi erant
kind of trapped in this architecture
genus haesit in architectura
from the late 80s and now they're you
a nuper 80s, et doluere mei estis
know they've been doing well with that
ipsi sciunt quia iam bene facitis
but now they're moving into more
ipsi erant 'magis nunc in motabilem
multimedia rich really game driven
vere dives ludum repulsi multimedia
multimedia driven and very decent
expulsis atque honestam bibendum
graphics cards integrated in the chip so
graphics pecto integrated in ut chip
the advantage of the a series is that
quod e re seriem
it's going to be lower power consumption
suus 'iens futurus inferioribus potentia consummatio
it's going to require a little bit less
suus 'iens aliquantulus requirere paulo minus
power it but it's going to be a little
sed id parum vox futurum
bit slower than the Intel but will that
nisi quod vult frenum tardius quam Intel
matter to you because here's the thing
quia materiam res hic
it's very much less expensive ok so in
plurimum in eam minus sumptuosus urna
your environment because you're gaming I
elit tibi, quia tu me forumque aleatoruml
think it would do just fine I think you
Puto esse ego facere sicut cogitant et bysso
do just fine with anything really that's
denique non modo ad aliquid quod suus 'vere
that's reasonably new i prefer intel
quod recte Novum I. potius Intel
because i'm a pretty you know I dry I
Im 'a pulchellus nosti me, quia ego sum excoquatur
drive these things to the to the ground
in eas quae in terram
and I push them really hard but for what
ventilabis eos et difficile, sed quod realiter
you're doing I think you do just fine
tu modo discis puto bene facitis
with finding a decent system that you
et excogitato system ut ad cultum
know is a good price point for you that
scio enim quia bonam pretio punctum vos
has a half-decent processor sounds like
processus est dimidium bonorum sonat,
you know enough about these things to
satis scire ea
know that yeah this is the better end of
scio quia melior est finis huius yeah
the the AMD series as far as multimedia
Intel series ornare in quantum
goes right but they're cheap because
quam vilis es recta
they are low end processors if you will
finem processus sis illae humiles
so so that's a cat you know this is just
ita ut a cattus scitis iustum est
kind of making a wise decision what I
tale quid facere arbitrium sapientis
would do though is price out price out
etsi hoc non ex pretio pretium est, de
to processors in the same price range so
et sic processus in pretium range
AMD vs intel say it's 200 bucks these
Vs Intel Pentium CC illos leones, quos isti dicunt suus '
two processors of the the same price how
de eodem pretio quo duos processus
do they compare now get on the internet
Nunc quia illi, compara ut in interrete
get on the google and say okay here's
ut hie bene dicere, et in Google scriptor
the AMD processor vs here's the intel
AMD processus est nos hic Intel
processor we already know that okay from
bene de nobis iam scitis ut processus
your research that these are about the
haec sunt quae de tua investigationis
same price and they're within your price
et ipse pretium es in pretio tuo
point so now get the benchmarks and see
ita ut iam ad designandum benchmarks quod animadverto
which one's going to perform better
unum praestare melius quam suus 'iens
because somebody out there on the
quia ibi est aliquid
internet almost guarantee ax has already
iam enim securis est fere penitus testamenti sponsor
tested those processors against each
processus inter temptasti eos
other and at the very least there will
nullum aliud saltem
be forums of people who say you know
et qui fora autem dico vobis: quia
here's the advantages to those specific
hic est illi ad propria commoda,
processors a jamison just reiterating
processors Jamieson solum in memoriam revocat
damn these good for budget systems if
hi damnant: Si bonum est budget systems
you want to if you want to go hog-wild
Si Vis ire volunt porcum, feram
with power and use a super amount of
Super utor a virtute et in copia
power then go Intel so true but a game
tum ut verae virtutis sed ad ludum Intel
that gap is kind of being bridged
illud ens ponte foramen
because AMD is creating better
quia meliora creavit Intel
processors with that a series so you you
sic et vos cum serie processors
could get away with that pretty well and
posse adepto satis bene et ut evacuandam
save some money but go Intel they don't
sed praeter pecuniam nolunt Intel
pay me to say that well there you have
redde mihi bene dicere non habetis
it cool mm-hmm now somebody was in the
hmm hoc frigus-mm in modo aliquem
chat room there just before we jump into
antequam salire sumus in chat cubiculum ibi
the news yep I'm sorry there was a
Ego paenitet erat ad nuntium yep
statement with regards to the previous
cum dicitur respiciens ad priorem
question I didn't want to miss it I hope
spero ego nolui mauris quaestio
I can catch it was it a gamoto fill me
Adimplebis me adsequi possum quod sit gamoto
in real quick I'm looking not seeing it
verum cum non sit velox apud Qui me?
I'm seeing a conversation about
Im 'de colloquium cum
starbucks there's Lana
starbucks est Lana scriptor
fun place to be if you're if you're here
Si vestri 'hic esse si vestri' amet locus
alive get into the chat room it's a lot
ut cum vivit in chat cubiculum quod suus 'multus
of fun and our websites category 5 TV is
V TV fun, et in nostrum genus est websites
the front end hub for all that stuff
supellectilem omnem finem respicit centrum
about installing a link USR slash bin
circa nexum installing usr VULNUS bin
slash G case you do know that's far
exacuere vade G apud vos scire quod suus 'tantum
that's too far back oh oh here we go all
Hie longius ire omne quod quis ad
over the map agra moto thank you at 724
Credo in tabula agra gratias ago tibi DCCXXIV
and 33 seconds talking about the the
cum autem et de XXXIII seconds
distribution and minimal install and and
et quod install distribution undique et ubilibet
having to use the internet to get
having utor penitus usque ad
updates this was Dan's question Dan a
haec updates est quaestio de Dan a Dan
gamoto says maybe this isn't what you're
maybe hoc est quod dicit gamoto te
looking for but would this not be a good
sed quaero ut hoc non erit vir bonus
case for the DVD install version of
si ad install versionem Hardcover
ubuntu know which is an interesting
scire an interesting quod sit Ubuntu
point because now when Dan said a gamoto
illud quod iam dixi, cum a Dan gamoto
that that he's using the in the
suus per se et in se
minimalist install of course I'm
sane me install minimalist
thinking okay minimal we gotta build
Redditus autem aedificatis purus minimam cogitationem
upon that but the DVD version comes with
in hoc autem est in CD version
pretty much everything so you can
sic vos can pulchellus multo omnia
install it without the repositories and
absque hoc quod install apothecas
then you can strip it down you can pull
tum stringe illud trahere
stuff out it's not gonna it's not gonna
suus 'suus' non agnus dei agnus sunt non supellectilem
be anywhere is as clean as the minimal
non inputabit eis quod minus usquam tam minimum est
because if you're trying to get away
nam si tu es trying ut auferat
from the gnome desktop or whatever then
Et quidquid de gnome escritorio
you're going to have problems but just a
difficultates, sed ut vos erant 'iens ut iustus
suggestion there that came in the
suggestion est, qui venit per
chatroom dan and I thought that that was
chatroom Dan, et cogitavi, quod hoc esset
worth mentioning as well just if you are
Si vos es iustus quoque dignum
stuck without internet then that's an
non adhรฆsit penitus esse igitur ut '
option for you as well that's good
optio vobis ut bene ut 'bonum,
suggestion and that's why we keep you
Et ideo hoc consilium custodiet
around chat room you're full of great
chat cubiculum plenam magnae circa tibi
ideas and they're just such a fun bunch
ideas et iustus ut fun fasciculum
yeah that's just the best mm-hmm oh you
suus 'optimus ut iustus yeah mm-O Vos hmm
ready for the news yeah take her away
parata ad nuntium yeah ut illam amanti abducerem
here are the top stories from the
Hic summo historias
category 5 TV news room China has
V genus TV News Sina locus est
revealed its newest supercomputer and
et novissima ejus revelatum supercomputadora
even though it's unlikely to crack the
etsi enim suus 'verisimile ad resiliunt
world top
vertice orbem terrarum
and something about this super computer
Super quod aliquid super hoc computatrum
has astonished the tech community it is
quae ad admirationem movere tech est civitas
power neither by intel or AMD processors
Intel Pentium processus per vim aut
revealed last week at a conference in
revelata ultima septimana ad colloquium apud
japan japan jinan china and profiled in
Japan Sinis et Iaponia Jinan sunt in profiled
the New York Times the sun light blue
New York Times sol lucem, blue
light MPP super computer uses a chip
Super computatrum chip utitur lux MPP
designed by the chinese themselves and
ac Sinensium amet
it's not the chinese micro process or
et non est processus Micro Seres
the supercomputing can the
potest enim in Supercomputing
supercomputing community was expecting
Supercomputing exspectat est civitas
in other words the chinese are
In aliis verbis in Seres es
developing to micro processors that
Micro processors quam developing
could shift not only bragging rights in
iactatus iura transferre non potuit
the worldwide super computer game but
sed in terrarum Super computatrum ludum
the general market for server chips jack
Jack eu foro ad communem servo
dongarra the university of tennessee
Universitatis Tennessee in dongarra
professor who oversees the annual list
anno autem, qui doctor oversees album
of the top 500 supercomputers told wired
de vertice D wired ad supercomputers
that this shows that there is a
quod ostendit, qui non est
significant effort underway in china to
significant conatus citatus esse in Sina
build multi-core processors that can be
quae potest esse multi-aedificare core processors
put into the world's fastest computers
posuit in mundi velocissimo computers
he cautions us not to think of this
cautos ne putet sibi
development strictly in terms of
progressus termini proprie
supercomputing saying there is a low-end
dicentes ubi est humilis-finem Supercomputing
that where these chips sorry there's a
ubi hi qui a eu contristati sunt
low-end that where these chips can work
Ut eu humilemque potest ubi
you can imagine these chips replacing
His eu potest imaginari te repositoque
all the Intel chips in China neither
omnis Intel neque eu in Sina
intel or AMD have commented as a bit of
Intel Pentium aut commentati quod aliquantulus of
fun yesterday for Halloween onstar
amet in turpis heri OnStar
offered its users a monster Dodger
et draconi qui est ejus obtulerunt users Dodger
service Terry inch director at OnStar
digiti ad director Michael ministerium OnStar
said how is a fun holiday and our new
et quomodo nos feriae dictum est a fun novum
monster Dodger service reflects that
monstro quod Dodger ministerium reflects
this year in addition to OnStar
hoc anno praeter OnStar
providing help to subscribers who need
praebes auxilium necessarium subscriptores
directions to the closest costume shop
ornatu tabernam proximam in partibus
or convenience store to pick up candy we
aut in commodum copia ut exciperent Candy
are offering families an entertaining
domos offerens delectabiles
button push opportunity subscribers
Signatores occasione dis button
looking for a Halloween treat yesterday
Et facies turpis vultus parumper hesterno
could push their blue on star button and
hyacinthinum et sidus illorum urna ut felis
ask for the location of the nearest
item ex proximis primi locum petere
monster and then dodge the potential
et draconi qui est potentiale ictos
encounter fun for the kids and brought a
Suspendisse accumsan adduxit in proelio
light-hearted mood to the emergency
-levis corde est modus subitis
service no Hillary yeah I mean that
vel servitium nihil sit, quod Hilarius non yeah
sounds cute and all fun and games yes
ludis bella sonare et adhuc amet
but but I don't want to find a monster
non autem nolo ut monstrum
why am i picturing a poor little
Quid pauperculum fingant
four-year-old or five year old sit in
quatuor aut quinque annos anno sedere
the back seat as OnStar says don't turn
quod dicit sede a tergo non convertam OnStar
left there's a monster down and the poor
relictis ibi prodigium et pauperem
kids like
sicut haedos
seriously scared out of their mind
vehementiam passionum amentiam incurrunt gravissime terrebis
because it's so realistic it's like the
Vestibulum ut est quod tam
movies it's like this is OnStar don't
movies sicut hoc quod est non OnStar
turn left there's a monster there that's
et draconi qui est rursus reliquit illic 'ut'
kind of crazy every stop the kids are
furiosum omni genere sistere haedi
never gonna go down that Street again
Non agnus, ut iret usque adhuc Street
they'll be like no oh yeah don't go
O Yeah nulla erit ne non
towards Billy's house there's a witch in
ad Puer scriptor in domum illic 'a pythonissam
the force or there oh yeah get her now
et vis est ut ea nunc heu yeah
petrified of their towns petrified oh
O defixit oppidorum defixit
boy Sweden has suffered its worst ever
Sweden pueri sui pessimi unquam passus est
data leak after an anonymous hacker
an anonymous cum notitia effluo Piratica
hijack the Twitter accounts of the
hijack ad rationes Twitter
prominent MP and release details of more
Details of release magis prominentibus MP,
than 90,000 private email accounts the
90.000 rationes quam privata email
hacker struck last week one he disclosed
Ultima septimana unum Piratica percussit detexit,
the password and email details of
Details of email password quod in
several Swedish political journalists
pluribus Swedish politica diurnariis
the identities the identities the
et identitates et identitas sunt
hackers identity remains unknown his
Forum identitatem ejus manet ignotum
online name though is SC 3 a 5 j so stay
Etsi enim nomen tuum online III SC V j ut maneat
away from him in an interview with
ab eo colloquitur
express a newspaper he said he had
exprimere quod sit diurna dixit:
masterminded the biggest internet breach
Penitus contritionem masterminded maximus
in Sweden's history to remind people to
In Suetia scriptor historiae est admonere homines
change their passwords more often he
mutata in Tesserae et saepius
said I'd up this information to let
Ego autem dixi Curabitur quoniam haec nota sibi sit
people know that they handle their
sciunt tractandi
information wrongly many web pages are
perperam plures paginas in notitia
not up to scratch and consumers need to
Non est opus est digitis, et consumers
know they should never use the same
sciunt nunquam eadem
passwords for different services on the
passwords pro diversis muneris in
web heey goes on to say this is how he
Sequitur textus heey ut diceret quid hoc esset
got in a Twitter accounts as well well I
tum etiam per rationes Twitter obtinuit me
thank you for that yeah be wearing yikes
gratias ago tibi quia non erit circumdatio yeah yikes
canonical plans to expand its a boon to
canonicam ad expand eius consilia impetratur
linux distribution so it could be used
Linux distribution ita posse adhiberi
on smartphones tablets and other touch
Suspendisse tactus in alias tabulas
interface consumer electronics said
Dixit interface dolor electronics
canonical founder Mark Shuttleworth
Mark conditor canonum Shuttleworth
referring to the average user shuttler
referendo ad mediocris user shuttler
said computers users are starting to do
users dixit computers facere incipiens sunt,
their computing across a broad array of
computandi sunt trans lata acies
despite the new devices a broader array
non obstante novi cogitationes amplius ordinata
of devices and form factors he also goes
forma dicitur quoque cogitationibus res
on to state that canonical wants to
ad statum canonicum in hoc vult esse
bring a boon to to all personal
adducere ad personale beneficium est
computing form factors on phones tablets
dextralia phones in forma computatis factors
and smart screens right now Shuttleworth
et nunc dolor screens Shuttleworth
is at the ubuntu developer summit in
est summa in elit est in Ubuntu
orlando
orlando
this conference he is hoping to raise
sperans se attollere conloquii
enthusiasm on the part of volunteer
favore volonum
developers who canonical will need to
developers et utile erit ad opus
help develop the platform and provide
et providere suggestum ad auxilium develop
applications for the expanding OS
applications pro OS expanding
Shuttleworth has effectively answered
Quae respondit efficaciter Shuttleworth
that Canonical's controversial move to
quod utile est motus controversia
the unity interface was done in part
parte actum unitate interface
because unity would be better suited to
quia unitas aptiores fore
work across different platforms
per aliud opus platforms
particularly those relying on
fretus maxime
touchscreen interfaces you can get these
touchscreen interfaces vos can adepto illis
full stories online at category 5 TV /
V online ad genus plenus tabulatorum TV /
newsroom the category 5 bikini newsroom
V NEWSROOM genus bikini newsroom
is researched by roy w not with
non est investigentur a Roy Latin
contributions from our super awesome
Conlationes a eximius amet
community of viewers you have a new
civitas autem habes novum viewers
story you think's worthy of honorary
honorarium fabulam putes dignum est
mention send us an email at newsroom at
Newsroom mentio apud nos in email
category 5 TV from the category 50 TV
V TV genus in genus L TV
news room I'm Hillary Rumble I should
Hilarius me debeo locus nuntium murmure
just say very special thanks to Dan who
sicut dicunt qui Dan nimis speciales gratias
contributed to the newsroom well Q and
et Q etiam operam ad newsroom
yeah really nice to be receiving your
yeah vere nice quod accipiens vestra
emails and your thoughts with regards to
et cogitationes fuere penes
what we should be talking about in the
quid loquetur in
news terrific tonight the show is
nuntium noctem spectaculum multam nimis qualis est,
brought to you in part by pogoplug and
et partim ad te Pogoplug
you'll find them online cap five dot TV
youll 'reperio vestri TV et dat quinque, cap online
/ pogoplug check out that awesome device
/ Pogoplug Lorem fabrica, quod terribilis
also playing a Calypso cat5 TV / Calypso
est etiam ludens Calypso Exigit CAT5 TV / Calypso Exigit
fun online game you can download the
a fun online ludum vos can download
free application right there on the
liberum applicationem rectum est in
website cap five dot TV / Calypso this
c website quinque dat TV / Calypso Exigit hic
is category 5 technology TV you'll find
V genus technology quod youll 'reperio vestri TV
us online triple w category five dot TV
Latin triplex genus online dat nobis quinque TV
i'm your host Robbie Ferguson I'm
Im 'non sum tuus exercitum Robbie Tacitus
Hillary rumble Hillary I don't know if i
Hilarius Hilarius sit murmur, ego nescio si
have mentioned it to you before but I
sed ante mentionem fecimus vobis
kind of saw that coming with the boom to
Videns autem ex transuerso ueniunt
and canonical did you just that drive
quam exercuerunt in te iustum et canonicum coegi
with ever since I've you know they've
et semper ex quo tu scis quia commune aut inmundum habent
introduced unity and taken over with
et unitatis in introduced Susceperunt
unity it's really felt touchscreen ish
unitatis suus 'vere sensit introitu touchscreen
oh yes I do remember you saying that
sic faciam tibi o meminisse dicens
data interface looks very is not it's
spectat notitia interface suus 'non nimis
like total design for this yeah totally
Sicut enim tota intentio memini prorsus
I do remember saying that yes but the
Non sic autem est meminisse me dicens
problem with that is it feels really
Difficultas autem est realiter sentit
awkward to me as a mouse user you're
quasi male hoc mihi user mus te esse
like I just want to poke my screen not
EGO iustus volo ut mihi in screen, non poke
yeah I know but it just it wouldn't it
yeah scio quod iustus est, sed hoc non esset,
wouldn't be comfortable it wouldn't work
Non opus non elit
even if I had a touch screen now there
Porro autem si tactus screen
are some nice devices out there I think
nisi quaedam cogitationes ibi puto
in particular there's the HP TouchSmart
maxime ubi est HP TouchSmart
for example right and just thinking
cogitare enim et iustum
touchsmart I'm just gonna do a quick
Im 'iustus a velox TouchSmart laudibus?
search yeah the reason I'm thinking
Yeah cogito rationem quaerere
about this particular device is a gap
De arte huius spatium
what was mentioning in the chat room
memoriam facientes in chat cubiculum quod erat,
that it just isn't practical because of
ut non solum propter practical
the the form factor of these things but
de forma factor autem horum
they're their device actually lays right
tu autem recta ponit illorum fabrica actually
down so it almost becomes a desktop
ut fere fit in desktop
style screen right yeah you're touching
yeah style screen recte facimus tibi
one on here so then i can see that
Et hie unus vides
working but then you're taking up this
sed tunc erant 'non operantes Sumpta est
huge footprint on your desk right versus
ingens footprint in vestri desk versus dextrum
a mouse or in my case I use a trackball
mus autem in re vel non utor a trackball
so I only I literally ante at footprint
ut ego litteram non in ante, uxรถris
on my desk so it doesn't make a lot of
Super mensam scriptoriam meam est non facere multum
sense for me I don't want a touch screen
sensus tactus screen pro me, quia nolo de
interface yeah don't like it don't want
yeah interface quod nolo, non amo
it I don't have the device for it but
id non habent, sed quia non fabrica
the canonical has announced Mark
Mark nuntiatum est utile,
Shuttleworth that at the ubuntu
Shuttleworth, qui in Ubuntu
developer summit today and yesterday had
heri et hodie elit arce erant
mentioned that that they are indeed
ut illam quidem
pushing toward mobile devices but I
Sed contra nititur mรณviles
don't have that so tonight we're going
Non enim sic erant 'iens nocte
to fall back in love with ubuntu and
et rursus cadere in amore cum Ubuntu
make it work for our mouse okay for our
mus nos ad bene faciendum opus
desktop computer the way that you expect
computatrum desktop exspectare te in via
it to the way that you want it to when
ita ut ad eam, cum voles
you're using your computer because I
quod es computatrum arca tua
don't know about you but that's what I
nescio, sed id quod est de vobis
use I mean I love my my mobile device to
Ego amo utor meum mean meam ad mobile fabrica
I want to see a boon to on my mobile
Volo video vidi aliquod bonum est mobilis a me
device I would love to see lubuntu on my
ut fabrica amo video vidi lubuntu meis
tablet but I don't want the tablet
Tablet, sed nolo ad Tablet
interface on my desktop fair enough fair
pulchrum satis est pulchra interface meo desktop
enough so i have ubuntu 11.10 see right
Itaque satis habeo Ubuntu vide rectum 11,10
out of the box I've got a boon to and a
ex arca archa Ego got aliquod bonum est, et
boon to 2d alright so let's log in with
2d ut lets 'Licuit ergo et in boon log
a recently changed password with a
Nuper mutata password est cum
recently changed password thank you to
Nuper mutata password ut gratias ago tibi,
avoid here comes so you're gonna see
ut ne hic est amet videre
exactly what I'm saying there we go ok
Im 'non dicens quod me prorsus itur ok
so imagine okay yeah I'm going to be
yeah bene cogitet, ita Im 'iens futurus
able to reach up with my finger and
pervenire possint, et cum digitus meus
touch all these buttons here it's got a
Hic tangit tot globulis obtinuit eam
real as I've talked about it on the show
Ego sicut ipsa loquebatur de illo in spectaculum
before it's designed for touch screen
ad eam ordinantur tactus screen
and it's obvious that it does
et suus 'obvious ut non
mind for touchscreen big bold buttons
mens enim touchscreen audere magnum Bullae
which is fine but it's not designed to
qui tamen suus 'non bene disposito est
be used by somebody who's using a mouse
in quis suus 'utendum, qui usus mus
so what I'm going to do is I'm going to
et quรฆ ego facturus est, Im 'iens
jump into my terminal because tonight
quia in hac nocte salire terminalibus
what I'm actually going to do I want to
Quod Im 'vere non iens ut volo
I want to walk you through the steps now
Volo enim vos ambulare per gradibus iam
of course the next version of perfect
tunc utique perfectus versionem
boom 2 is going to actually do all this
II ad BUTIO sit actu omne
for you there's going to be a little
futurum est enim parum
toggle switch that allows you to
switch quod sino vos ut toggle
basically convert 11 point 10 into a
plerumque vertunt XI punctum X in
gnome to style desktop based on an older
style fundatur in desktop gnome, est maior
version of the boon to but what I want
Volo autem quod est versionem in boon
to do is I want to show you exactly how
ut non sit exacte quomodo vos volo ostendere
this is done and what it is that we're
et hoc est quod nos
actually doing yeah dad will were not
yeah non operetur Pater meus
indeed switching to Nome two point three
switching ad Taphnis quidem duo punctum tres
point two or 2.32 we want to actually
2,32 iam enim duos aut ut vere volo
stay with gnome 3 we're not going to
mane apud gnome III erant 'non iens
downgrade your computer instead we're
pro computatrum downgrade vestri sumus
going to make your computer compatible
'iens ut computatrum tuum compatible
with this interface okay we're not going
hoc bene interface erant 'non iens
to use gnome shell we're not going to do
gnome, cortice ut erant 'non iens ut faciam
any of that stuff so here I am in the
ita hic sum illius in omnem supellectilem
terminal okay on my brand new out of the
terminalibus bene novam de me
box i haven't touched anything it's just
ego arca archa quod suus 'iustus non tetigit
it's got its updates and that's it this
suus 'got ut' non hoc suum ac updates
is a boon to 11 point so I'm going to go
XI punctum sit donum a deo, ita Im 'iens exire
first of all sudo hmm oh I do have mouse
Primum omnium sudo quia non O mus hmm
or a keyboard there we go just a little
Non nos aut parum tincidunt
slow
tarda
hello sudo apt-get update is the first
salve primus update adepto apta sudo
thing you want to run that's going to
quod suus 'iens rem vis currere
get your up-to-date repository
sursum-ut-balanus adepto vestri armarium
information enter your password as
ignoro ingressus est notitia
necessary there we go it's gone through
Necesse est enim ut suus 'absentis per
my updates it's going to get those off
illa suus 'iens impetro off mea updates
the internet for me okay so the first
Penitus est primum sic bene mihi
thing that I want to do is I want to get
Volo impetro res est quam vis ut faciam tibi
the ability to take kubuntu back to a
facultatem ad repetunt kubuntu
gnome to style interface now in order to
gnome style interface est ut iam
do that I'm going to use session fall
Im 'iens ut facere sessionem ruinam
back so that's where the fall back comes
et reversus est retro fit ubi in ruinam
in session fall back is going to allow
sedente autem passurus relabuntur
us basically to flip that switch when we
nos basically ut switch ut flip cum
first turn on our computer it turns into
primum computatrum rursus vertit in nobis
a session so and it's actually what's
Et quid suus 'vere non tam sessionem
what you're going to recognize if you
quod erant 'iens ut si agnoscis
are installing gnome shell similar kind
similia sunt conchae insertis gnome
of thing but we're going to do this with
est aliquid, sed erant 'iens per hoc
as minimal you know amount of stuff as
tu scis quod minimum in quod moles supellectilem
possible when I type it seems to be
posse cum typus videtur esse
taking a moment to get in there you are
et in tempore suo moram facit ut sint ibi
faster than the computer there we go
citius quam itur computer est
yeah I don't know what that's about okay
yeah nescio quid de okay ut '
so sudo apt-get the dash install and
sudo, ita ut facile install, et impetu
then gnome session there should be a
et gnome senatum foret
dash there let's fix it there we go okay
illic pedem figere lets 'okay ad eam ibi
so you can see that now sudo apt-get
sic vos can animadverto, quod, ut modo aptius sudo
install gnome session fall back all
gnome relabuntur institutionem omnem senatum
right nice and simple this is going to
et nice quod simplex is est iens recta
give us about 40 Meg's worth of stuff
date nobis de Meg XL scriptor pretium of supellectilem
and once that's in we're going to be
et quod olim apud nos erant 'iens futurus
able to switch our session over to gnome
possunt flectendum ad gnome nostri sessioni
classic without having to install
ut install sine classic
Lubuntu shell or gnome shell pardon me
Putamine nucem veniam Lubuntu et gnome,
there we go 40.2 megs of additional
40,2 in imus est megs additional
stuff you'll notice that we are we're
supellectilem youll 'animadverto ut sint sumus
going to get the ala carte menu editor
going to get the ala biga menu Editor
as well as a couple of other things but
sed etiam alia duo
we're not getting the full out
erant 'non questus de plenum
gnome-shell it's going to be really
suus 'iens esse vere placebunt gnome,
quite minimalist and it's only 40 point
et tantum XL suus 'iam satis minimalist
to Meg's so we're going to say yes to
Meg sic erant 'iens dicere quod sic est scriptor
that we're going to let that go and
quod erant 'iens ut fiat et id
again it's actually installing all this
item omne quod suus 'vere installing
stuff Hilary right off yeah the Internet
Internet Hilario supellectilem ius off yeah
I don't need
Non opus
risks this is where it really comes in
Hoc periculum est, ubi vere est, in
handy to have that high-speed internet
habilis sunt qui est summus celeritas Penitus
connection right so this is going to go
nexum et ius quo iturus
through and get all that stuff for us
per supellectilem atque omnia quae ad nos
it's pretty good pretty good moving
suus 'pulchellus bonus pulchellus bonum movens
pretty pretty good speed this is
satis est pulchellus bonus celeritas
category 5 technology TV and you'll find
V TV genus technology quod youll 'reperio
us online at category five dot TV we
Quinque online at genus hoc dat nobis TV
welcome your questions and your
rogationibus tuis et receperint
questions are what direct the show's
interrogationes sunt quae dirigunt spectaculum scriptor
content category 5 you can email us live
V Vivamus email potes contentus genus
at category five dot TV please send me
Mitte ergo mihi placet, dat TV in genus quinque
emails excited reading them any co-host
et omnem exercitum cooperatores legis dolor emails
us but I'm just saying to do it just do
Im 'iustus tamen nos id facere sicut faciunt dicens
it all right that's coming along get
per illud jus venit, quod suus 'possidebit
them the panel applet this is alive this
haec illis vivimus APPLET Panel
is happening in real time yes see
tunc videbis quod sic fieri et in esse reali
exactly pardon me exactly how long this
veniam prorsus prorsus iste quousque
takes and how to go about doing it there
et se ipsam ad benefaciendo
we go it is done yeah it's a deferred
Yeah imus fit suus differtur
some processing there we go okay so now
pars processus est bene imus, et nunc,
let's simply log out of our computer
lets simpliciter computatrum log ex nobis
click on the the gear up at the top left
click in summo usque ad calces ad sinistram
I think I'm probably working this thing
Ego puto hoc est probabiliter opus
to death I'll figure that out
youll 'instar sicco quam usque ad mortem et
I'm just going to close that see if that
Im 'iustus iens ut videam si claudere
makes any difference there you go okay
Accumsan interesse Grat
click on the gear and then go log out
click in calces et tunc ire de log
are you sure you want to close all
Visne tu claudere
programs and log out of the computer i'm
Im 'computer progressio e log
going to say yeah login i'm pretty sure
Im 'pulchellus certus iens dicere yeah login
yeah that's what we want to do here we
yeah Nunc illud est quod si vis ut faciam tibi
go alright so now you're going to see
Nunc erant 'iens ut videre licet ire
that if we click here we have known
Nos scimus quia hic click
classic that's what that gave us so
qui dedit nobis classic Hoc illud est quod tam
switch it okay so i've switched that to
switched ad hoc quod bene switch ut Ive '
gnome classic we're no longer selecting
gnome non erant classic lectio
lubuntu right all right enter your
iure omnia intra lubuntu
password and hit enter and here we go so
Hic autor tam intrare password
this is step one this is going to get us
id est unius gradus est iens impetro nobis
to that kind of classic style lubuntu
ad quod genus classic style lubuntu
desktop okay and remember we didn't have
memento nos non habere et bene desktop
to install gnome shell here ok now we're
ok ut install gnome, testa nunc hic sumus
going to go up to our name click on it
ut ascenderent ad click nomine
and go system settings once we're in
et ratio occasus ut semel es apud nos
there we're going to go into appearance
ingressus es ad apparentiam ibi
and now this is a little bit of a
et nunc hoc est paulo frenum de
workaround what I'm going to do is I'm
quรฆ ego facturus sum non habemus
going to change my theme down at the
ad mutare mea usque ad theme
bottom here okay change it from ambience
imo hic bene sit mutatio de ambience
to radians and that's going to get rid
et radians ut 'iens impetro rid
of the black and just turn it to a nice
et mox in nigrum conversus autem ad a nice
kind of gradient rice okay so that works
Proin purus cliuos ut opus quoddam
okay i'm going to close out of that now
Bene ergo de claudere ibo
going to go back into terminal cuz we're
'iens ut terminus in cuz sumus
going to learn the terminal tonight okay
ad ultimam discere bene nocte
there's two things left that i want to
Duo sunt quรฆ reliquit illic 'volo,
install so i'm going to go sudo apt-get
ita Im 'iens impetro ut install sudo oris sui,
install you're going to love this human
install vos erant 'iens ut homo amat hoc
dash seem ok I'm going to do this on
ok videtur unquam offendas ad me hoc est
Tula on one line so we can install the
Tula una linea possumus installauit
theme and I'm going to install g comp
Im 'iens ut install lemma et g d
dash editor ok so we're going to get
ok ut erant 'iens impetro Editor de latibulis surrexissent
that original human theme from a boon to
quod originale munus humanum ex theme
and we're gonna get the g comp editor so
g ad d ita ut amet et Editor
that we can edit our G configuration
ut nos can emendo G configuratione
there you go this is going to give us
Ad hoc nos Grat
for megs of data all right much better
nam omnia Megs magis notitia
response time now I much prefer the
placet tantum nunc in tempore responsum
human beam to the zombie theme yeah you
trabem autem humana est Zombie theme yeah
know something about zombies their theme
theme illorum sciunt aliquid de immortui
ambience kind of feel zombie ish with
quaedam sentire cum viris ambience Zombie
all the darkness yes so it's done all
tenebrae insuper omnibus omnia factum ut
right beauty so that's done and done so
iure factum esse voluisti decore
what I want to do is now i'm going to
quid vis ut faciam tibi nunc Im 'iens
type the words g comp dash editor ok so
typus verbis d g de latibulis surrexissent Editor est ok
now this is my configuration editor i'm
hoc est autem configuratione Editor sum
going to go into apps and then we want
volumus et ingredere ad Apps
to find Matassa tea or metacity
ut Matassa tea vel metacity
hello that's telling me see this is
Quod suus 'vera salve me, hoc est,
what's neat about when you run something
Quid tersus res circa Cum current,
through the terminal so you can see the
in terminum, ut possis videre
actual errors yeah and it says that
ipsa ignorantia et dicit yeah
there is a problem their index value too
Index sua pretii est etiam a forsit
large just in case i'm going to log out
Im 'iustus iens magnum si de log
and then log back in because i haven't
tum quia non in stipes et
done that since installing the theme and
quia et materia fit inaugurari
g comp config not having to reboot the
non ut reboot d g config
whole computer you'll notice that gnome
quod youll 'animadverto totus es computatrum gnome,
classic is now set as my default so i'm
set quod default et nunc est classic mei sum
always going to get that g Siegel thinks
ut semper ad id cogitat g Siegel
that I like to live on the wild side I
ut vivant ut in me feram plagam
would agree yeah definitely if you'd
Si nunc certe non conveniunt yeah
like if you want to use the inner add
sicut si velis uti ad interiorem addendi
the GUI at this point you can just go
in hac parte vos can iustus vado in GUI
down the system tools configuration
in systema instrumenta configuratione
editor there we go alright a logout and
Editor est autem concludere licet nos eamus, et
login did it for us and I've brought up
login fecit nobis, et adduxi eum
apps Matassa t Windows users you'll
T apps Matassa Fenestra users youll
recognize this it looks very much like a
Hanc videtur simillimus
registry okay so here's what we want to
et hinc est quod nos volo ut subcriptio bene
do scroll down and you'll see one called
librum qui vocatur et videbis
theme all right I can double click on
theme omni iure possum in geminus click
the word radiance remember we changed it
si mutavit ea meminisse verbi lumen eius
to radians well that's good because now
radians ad bonum, quod iam bene
GDK theme is set to radians but now we
Nunc autem posuit ad radians est: theme GDK
want our Matassa t theme set to human
theme vis noster Matassa T profectus est ad hominem
with an uppercase h if i hit enter see
Si ego ledo ingrediuntur, videatur verbo ire cum h
what happened oh it looks very much like
O factum videtur simillimus
the original Ubuntu human theme i see so
in homine originale Ubuntu lemma ut ego animadverto
now there's one thing that's that's left
Aliud est quod nunc relictus
to do here and that's these bad boys so
ita hic quod illa facere nil
scroll up a little ways okay and you see
Bene autem vides pusillum librum
button layout double click on the value
geminus click in puga pyga layout pretii
of the right and we want to change that
De iure et volunt mutare
order so first of all we want to put the
in primis volumus tam
colon which is the the name of the
quem colonia est nomen
program and then these are going to be
et hi progressio sunt futura esse
relational to that so I'm going to
non obviat relationis ut sic Im 'iens
highlight the word close and cut it and
et interficiam claudere atque optatum eo spectabant verbum
I'm going to paste that at the end but
Im 'iens est igitur, quod in fine, sed
I'm going to add a comma after maximize
Im 'iens ut maximize addere, postquam interiecto commate
all right hmm so now and now I've got to
hmm et omnia recta iam nunc et Ego got
delete that last colon because that's
quia illud quod est ultimum colonia delere
where it was okay so now it looks like
ubi erat tam bene iam vultus amo
colon min
colonia min
mais maximize clothes when i hit enter
mais maximize vestimenta sua Cum ledo intraveritis
ah okay I've moved those now you'll see
Ego ah bene motus qui nunc te video
that there's one other thing missing
deest enim est alius
from the top left hand side okay so
Bene igitur summo sinistram
before that colon I'm going to add the
ante colonia Im 'iens subinfero
word menu okay and hit enter and you'll
verbum quod ledo menu intraveritis, et bene tibi faciam,
see that now I have oh sweet your
videantur quae nunc habeo, o dulcis tua
standard menu just as you would have
vexillum menu Iustus ut vos would have
okay so now the final button layout says
tam bene iam puga pyga layout dicit finalem
menu colon minimize comma maximize comma
Comma maximize minimize menu colonia distingue
close full stop no period okay so that's
tempus prope plenum prohibere non ut suus 'okay
all there is to that now final step is
inde nunc est quod omnia ultima gradus est,
basically okay we've got the theme we've
bene nobis inest plerumque Comperto autem theme
got all that working let's just kind of
fugit omnis generis laborandi iusto
finalize it we're going to do that with
denique sic erant 'iens ut faciam cum eo
something that's already included with
aliquid includitur quae iam receptae apud
11.04 Lubuntu we're going to go straight
11.04 Lubuntu erant 'iens ut recta
to another orange theme grab those
theme aliud aureum et capto eos
leaves close out of that and now if you
Si ergo fuerit de propinquo
bring up your Nautilus window you'll see
bring up tua nautilus fenestra youll 'animadverto
this feels much more like home much more
quanto similior quanto magis domus haec sentit
like the old style of them too much more
sicut etiam vetus quanto magis modus earum
like you know gnome too but yet we're
et gnome, est tamen sicut scitis sumus
still looking at gnome 3 believe it or
etiam aspiciens ad gnome sit credere seu III
not we're still looking at ubuntu 11.10
nos erant 'adhuc respiciens ad Ubuntu 11,10
have access to a boon to software center
illi beneficium aditus ad centrum software
you still have the ability to install
Adhuc enim habes facultatem install
the applications that you can get on a
quod applications vos can adepto ad in
boon to 11 point 10 with unity just that
XI, quod sicut punctum X per unitatis in boon
you're not trapped into that unity
Non es capti in hoc unitatis
interface you now have a much more
interface est tibi ut multo amplius
familiar interface couple of things are
quae nota sunt de duobus interface
a little bit different you'll see that
quod youll 'animadverto aliquantulus diversis paulo
the clock is centered up here that can
horologium sitas ad hoc quod possumus usque huc
be moved you'll see that system settings
occasus youll 'animadverto quod motus est ratio
is still on my name and shut down logout
et clausa est nomen meum concludere
and restart is under shut down as well
et in hoc clausa ut sileo
when you reboot your computer everything
quae cum reboot vestri computer
is going to remain everything is hard
difficile est omnia est iens ut maneant
set now and you're not going to lose
iam non es set perdere
those settings if you reboot so that is
fundis ut si is qui reboot
now your interface you can go onto the
Nunc potes ire tuum interface in onto
internet find yourself a great wallpaper
Penitus te ipsum invenies magnam wallpaper
a desktop wallpaper good place to start
a bonus locus ut satus Caelum Desktop Wallpaper
is Nome dash look dot org and there you
is vultus in Taphnis de latibulis surrexissent, et ibi dot org
will find some gtk licensed
invenies aliquo gtk licentiati
desktop wallpapers and themes and things
wallpaper lemma desktop quod omnia et
like that so that's just to get you
quae qualis est mox ut vos adepto ut
started making them boon to 11 point 10
XI punctum X facere coepit illis in boon
feel a little bit more like the old
sentio parum aliquantulus magis sicut vetus
style of boon to and that's what's going
Et quid suus 'iens ut qui modus boon
to help you to fall back in love with
ad auxilium vobis amare cadere retrorsum
boom to with 11 point 10 mm kick it at
XI punctum ad BUTIO in hoc tempore calce X mm
old school old school old school love
ludum vetus vetus vetus schola schola caritate
indeed this is category 5 technology TV
hoc quidem genus technology V TV
you'll find us online at triple w
youll 'reperio nostrum online at Latin triplum
category five dot TV just a couple of
genus dat quinque, iustus TV duobus
minutes left if you can believe right at
minutes reliquit potes credere, si ad rectam
the end of show how I'm fun I tell ya
Im 'fun ad extremum ostendit quomodo me narrare ya
yeah any questions for us in the chat
yeah quis quaestiones nobis ad chat
room hey hey yeah let us know quicktime
nescis heu heu locus yeah Venite QuickTime
if you got anything to say you know did
Si vos got aliquid dicere scis fecit
he dress up yesterday did i yes I was
Etiam hesterno die fecerunt in me ego autem exhiberet convivium
the queen of hearts the queen of hearts
regina in cordibus regina in cordibus vestris
you she hasn't seen last week's show
Ultima septimana scriptor ostendit tibi quรฆ non vidistis
people I didn't but I did I check out
sed ego non reprehendo populus
the website i did see some pics of the
ego did animadverto quaedam in website de pics
costumes which I liked yes I really
Ego vere probaverunt quod sic indumenta
enjoyed she still doesn't know she still
usque tamen non sciunt illa, voluptati fuit, non
doesn't know watch episode why teams
Quare res vigiliam lobortis nescit
just tell me well you said you were the
iustus dico me ad vos, bene dixisti
queen of hearts but on last week's show
Ultima septimana scriptor regina cordibus et in spectaculum
what was I haha free shop let's go to
quod liberum tabernam et eamus in me haha
the category five dots yeah cuz you go
Genus dots yeah quinque ad cursa eras
to photo gallery what sort of fun things
quae qualis sit amet est photo
are online Robbie's always always doing
Robbie suus 'semper online in facio semper
these fun little these little updates
modicum pusillis istis updates amet
all the time we don't know what's
omni tempore nescimus quid
happening so the only way you can stay
tantum modo fieri ut possitis
connected is by checking it out all the
id omne conligatum annotando
time oh my lanta is I ever funny for
O mihi in me est semper ridiculam ad tempus Lanta
that awesome and you just happen to be
ne forte te et horribilis
the queen of hearts what are the odds oh
Quid sunt odds o regina in cordibus vestris
I Wow Erica awesome yeah we had a lot of
Erica cinerea et Wow yeah habuimus multum horribilis
fun I am nicer Chris I know trick or
ego melior amet te scio cautela Chris
treating ya he was captain Zach and I
Puer autem erat prรฆfectus Zach et restituet
was commander daddy oh my god cute
O Deus meus, dux esset tata cute quod
thought I was very much as Spock and and
Existimabam ut plurimum ac Spock
if I could count the number of people
Si numerare numerum
who said oh look at you little guy star
qui dixit quis viderit inquiens stella
wars and you're like that's I threw out
Quod ut 'non nimium abiectis et quasi bella ex
the candy from that house this is poison
a Candy in domo, quod est venenum
poison
venenum
just place filled with just terrible
Terribilis est locus templo repleti iusta iustum
things unbelievable a couple people got
populus got a copulabis rerum incredibilem
it though some people were like they
ut etsi qui fuerunt alii similis illi
thought it was the coolest one guy I
unus homunculus putavit frigidissima
mean look at me people look at me and
respice ad me et da mihi osculum sibi volunt homines
one guy walked up to me said dude you
Unum guy dixit ad me abiit autem dude
even got the haircut for it you're like
et surrexit TONSUS quia amo te
yeah I just kind of say that that walked
yeah me sicut quidam dicunt, quod ambulavit
away I went into I went into a fast-food
et ingressus intravi ieiunium
restaurant cuz I I got off work and I
II popina cuz got off labor et
zip right home got the kids and we went
avi domum obtinuit recta ad haedos et abierunt
out I got dressed and went out I didn't
I got indutus sum, et non exivit de
get dinner until 830-9 so I starvin just
830-9 ad prandium adepto ut iustus starvin
figured I'd pick up something quick so I
figured ego colligunt usque ut aliquid velox
just I didn't do the drive-thru I don't
sicut et ego non sum, non per coegi-thru
know I'm dressed up i'm gonna got it you
Im 'agnus dei indutus est scire Im' non obtinuit eam
know this thing is like am I didn't wear
scitote res est ut ego non induendum
it to work because it just didn't it
illud nonne iustum opere
didn't work with the the yeah this year
et memini hoc cum parum
well I would have been the only one
ut etiam unum tantum esse
dressed up and everyone would have been
et omnis indutus fuisset,
laughing and cheering it would have been
ridentes ad cohortandos milites non fuisset,
like high school so I just figured I'd
sicut princeps schola instar sicut et ego mallem
avoid that whole situation so but it was
ne totum hoc tempus sed
kind of neat to be driving around as
quaedam lepida in circuitu sicut driving
Spock and people actually thought it was
Spock populo et vere cogitari esse
cool instead of dorky oh yeah I went
yeah veni venias frigus pro dorky
into this fast food place and they just
in cibum et iustus
they thought it was a riot like that's
quod cogitavi ut 'similis erat luxuria
not everybody coming out from the
non venient ab omnibus
kitchen and stuff and come to see me can
et culina supellectilem et potest videre,
you do the Vulcan hand thing that's so
factaque Volcani manibus paria feceritis, id est ita
cool and they're trying and they're like
ipsi erant 'trying ut et tu et frigus
yeah so that was the joy of I like that
yeah est gaudium de te, ut placet
I admire your boldness to know boldness
Admiror amittere confidentiam vestram cognoscere audaciam traducis
would begin their on November 15th
ut in primo die November 15
through true i guess july you know just
July per verum i coniecto sicut scitis
in the part of july just we're gonna get
'agnus dei adepto erant' iustus pars in July
n two eras aren't I i double-dog dare
Duo sunt tempora canis ausus gemina i n
you while in the similar vein um Trek
Similiter dum in vobis um Trek
eNOS there was an email that came in not
Non fuit inscriptio eNOS ingredienti
exactly um good question but a photo oh
um sed a photo utinam prorsus bonum quaestio
yeah sent into us from leland saying a
yeah in nos missum ait ad leland
captain and Spock where's the Wirecast
unde et quinquaginta qui Spock est Wirecast
Enterprise bridge tell Scotty not to
Non dico Caledoni expeditione pontis
beam us up until after they bring us our
lignum post nos perducunt nos
dinner and here is the photo from let's
et a puncto s photo de Ecce prandium
see if I can pull this up our viewer
si possum trahere videtis haec usque nostra videntium
Leland I haven't seen this yet Leyland
Lelandus tamen non videtur quod Leyland
oh the road
O iter
surprise surprise okay I'm gonna save
Im 'agnus dei mirum mirum nisi bene
this to my desktop oh well check it out
mihi quoque obsecro ut escritorio look
like I'm gonna Leland a little bit of
ut Im 'agnus dei Lelandi Antiquarii de exigua,
your point well just gotta sound knows
punctum bene novit iustus Redditus sonus vester
his way yeah there we are so what's the
yeah viis suis non sunt ut ea quae nobis est
what's the description of this this says
Quid huic descriptioni dicit
again a captain and Spock where is the
rursus ubi est unum ex centurionibus, Spock
Wirecast Enterprise bridge tell Scotty
Inceptum Wirecast pontem dico Caledoni
not to beam us up until after they bring
prius trabem non perducunt nos
us our dinner there we go thanks Leland
Lelandus noster nobis gratiam ad cenam ibi
yeah that would be fun we haven't done
Yeah fun quae non fecimus
much green screening we've been doing
multa nos Ive 'been effectus viridi protegendo
some testing I did a stress test over
testis enim mihi de accentus super temptare
the weekend and thank you to those of
et gratias ad eos in volutpat vestibulum
you who participated basically we took
plerumque non operam cepimus
the new server and we said okay well how
et dixerunt quomodo tam bene novi servo
much can we really push through this
ventilabis per haec quantum possumus realiter
thing we did green screen and it was
viridi screen est non fecit quod erat
phenomenal like everyone performed so
ut quisque tarn mirabile
well I think it's going to be possible
puto suus 'iens ut bene poterit
and and so maybe there is a chance
ac facultas et maybe est
Leland that we will see some green
Lelandus, qui viride aliquid videbimus
screening during the live broadcast cuz
in protegendo vivere passim cuz
Wirecast is fully capable of that really
Wirecast potuisse satis ut realiter
what it comes down to is how good is our
quod bonum est nos descendit
lighting so we might need to get some
lux lucis ut nos postulo ut aliquid
lighting for the backdrop if we wanted a
Si enim volens hoc deponens ad benignum exo-
new green screen and also how good is
et nova viridi screen quid sit bonum,
the camera as you can tell the
ut possis dicere quod in camera
wide-angle camera that we're using its
quia erant 'usura late angulus camera sua
1080p but the I don't know if is the
1080p sed nescio si est,
lens or what it is but it's not as
aut quid est illud, sed quod suus 'non lens
crystal clear as here we've got a 720p
liquide constat quod hic Comperto 720p
camera that is just it's just so sharp
quod hoc camera iustus est sicut et acri
and beautiful and you know it's just
et suus 'pulchra et scitis iustum
getting to that point where we have
ut questus ut punctus in quo habemus
cameras that are that sharp and
qui sunt qui cameras et acri
unfortunately you know the big cameras
Scitis enim magnus valde dolendum cameras
like the professional cameras they run
sicut currunt illi cameras professional
into the tens 20s 30s thousands so
ad decem milia et 20s 30s
they're very pricey I don't see us doing
quod nos facere non nimium carus
that anytime just right away but but one
sed quod una se quisquam iustum
day season 15 will get there oh yeah we
die XV temporum enim erit nobis O yeah
do well with what we have and we've
bene facitis quod habemus et nos Ive '
refined everybody's support and it's
Non omnibus ignis probabuntur multi: et suscipio suus '
been it's been tons of fun i'm so
Im 'tons of fun et suus' been sunt
excited that season five is here and
Et commotum est quinque temporum
we're doing well i know having a fun
Scio enim benefacientes si erant 'habens fun
time fabulous yeah and we're just gonna
yeah fabulosa tempora iustus et agnus
get better and better every season
melius et melius omni tempore
always improving always new things
semper ascendere, semper nova sunt
coming it's great yeah
yeah venturus est magnus,
what's going on the chat room dad will
Pater autem quod suus 'iens ex chat cubiculum
like cat will got a teenage mutant ninja
sicut feles Teenage Mutant Ninja iaculis et possedi
turtles snuggly like I'm talking moo moo
Im 'turtures snuggly sicut locuti moo moo
here and and we put him on green screen
posuit et tentorium in virides passim
and it was it was amazing his whole body
erat totus erat miris
disappeared but here's what was cool i
hic est frigus: sed quid ego disappeared
said to God well you have green eyes
Dixit quoque Deus viridi habes oculos
don't you and he's like why yeah I do
memini quid faciam vobis et non amo
and he had two holes in his head oh
O caput et duo foramina
that's it and you could see the scene
Quod ut 'eam, et non vident scaenam
behind him a turkey it was pretty
Turcia ei a tergo erat pulchellus
awesome but it makes you think okay well
terribilis autem vobis videtur bene, bene facit
what happens if you're doing green
Si quid agis virentibus
screening and you have something set
et habes quod paro protegantur
with green eyes because it was it was
quia oculi eius virentibus
guy obviously gap what will tell you
Guido manifesto gap, quid dicam vobis
that it was it was very obvious but
Manifestum est autem quod ipsa
we'll definitely find some screen grabs
nos certus youll 'reperio screen alicuius temere id capessit
at some point of that yeah definitely
in aliquo puncto illius certus yeah
grab those because those up hilarious
in quibus quia hilarem iaculis
yeah I never would have thought I'd pick
Non memini velim legas crederes
up on all right guys like that
guys in ius quasi
sensitivity yeah boy that's wild
yeah quod anima trahitur puer ferox
apparently God will has changed his
videtur quod Deus non habet arbitrium vertit
avatar on the website tall from that
ex longa site in any
encounter screen so if you have a link
perspiciatis unde si vinculum elit
to your profile gadwal that i can bring
ad quam possum deducere profile gadwal
up real quick we've only got 30 seconds
verum velox et nos Ive 'tantum got in XXX seconds
left on the show we'd love to check it
manet enim ostendimus amabis sisto
out but i'll be happy little somethin
et beatus eris sed paulo somethin
somethin mm-hmm it's kind of funny
somethin mm hmm, suus 'ridiculam genus
actually I'm impressed with that
actually Ego impressa est cum eo
surprising everybody have fun this week
mirumque omnibus habere fun hoc septimana
learn lots we hope so if if you send a
sortem mitte te scire ita speramus
question and didn't hear from us please
quaestione audire, et non nobis placere
let us know but we do try to attend to
sciamus nos intendere experiamur
all your questions in a timely fashion
omnia quaestiones in opportune modo
mmm but live at category five dot TV
mmm autem dat TV vivunt in genus quinque
that's where the party's at people
quod in populo ubi pars scriptor
Michael Iowa joining us again tonight
Michael Iowa veniendo iterum hac nocte
Cameron Greg and Texas agamotto nice to
Cameronis et Texas agamotto bellum ut Greg
see you the old gang drumstick of course
sane veteres turbae te clavicula
yeah zit 1965 good to see ya AAS 759
yeah zit MCMLXV ad bonum Puer AAS DCCLIX
cheers and and some reminders to write
et magna laude et memoria scribere
us letters minus letters yeah send us
Yeah litteras nobis miseris litteris minus
your send us here at write postcards
hic tibi scribere nobis Postcards
you'll post in the mail the post will
Prescriptio in manibus tabellariorium est autem post post te
check it and brilliant leaks by timing
Morbi libero a coerceret praeclaraque
yet to receive your post cool i may not
sed ne ad auram post te
be I'd be awesomes what is really
vellem autem esse quid realiter awesomes
oh yeah well um got a little something
O yeah um obtinuit tam parum aliquid
to show people I'm working on it yeah
Im 'opus in eo ostendere populo yeah
some Joker made it so that you had to
Scurra quidam fecit ut esset,
log in in order to Oh your profiles Oh
ut log in O, o vestri profiles
Robbie unbelievable security great
Robbie incredibilis securitas magna
security and there he is Oh II oh but
et ibi est et o, o securitas II
he's got his sunglasses on oh but that's
oh ut 'verum ejus hes' got oculariorum solariorum
part of what you can see our stars okay
potes videre quod bene de stellis
behind his his memory boo boo brilliant
post insignem memoriam boo boo
all right well thanks God well thanks
omni iure tam bene gratias agentes Deo
everybody have a wonderful wonderful
mirabilis in omnibus mira sunt
week so nice having you here nice to see
ita nice quod hic septem habens nice videre
ya and we'll talk to you next Tuesday
ut Martis proximo lente tibi ad os loqui:
night seven o'clock high good night
horam noctis Bono nocte